929 N. Wolfe St., Unit 801 Baltimore, MD 21205 Mobile: 617-286-9618 Email: xxuzhang@jhsph.edu

PROFILE

Master of Public Health student concentrated on Epidemiology and Biostatistics. Capstone project with experience of contact of Community Health Workers' service in Bangladesh. Research assistant with experience of community based primary care in children and maternal health in poor settings. Practicum project with experience of Chronic Kidney Disease management in South Asian and benchmark to developed countries. HIV consultant volunteer serving in a NGO founded in Chicago. Fluent in English and Chinese Mandarin.

EDUCATION

Master of Public Health (MPH), GPA: 3.66/4.0

Expected May 2014

Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health (JHSPH), Baltimore, MD

Concentration: Epidemiology and Biostatistics

Relevant Coursework (to be completed by May 2014): 3 terms of Epidemiologic Methods, 4 terms of Biostatistics, the Tools of Public Health Practice and Decision Making, Population Dynamics and Public Health, Fundamentals of Budgeting and Financial Management, Malariology, Social and Behavioral Foundations of Primary Health Care, Introduction of SAS

Bachelor of Medicine (MD Equivalent), GPA: 4.5/5.0

June 2013

Tongji University, Shanghai, China

Honors: Shanghai Outstanding Graduates, National Scholarship in China

EXPERIENCE

Research

MPH Capstone Project

Oct. 2013- Present

Access to the Utilizations of Community Health Workers' Service in Bangladesh from 1995 to 1998 JHSPH, Baltimore

- Merged dataset of different formats into STATA
- Summarized the distribution of demographics status using STATA
- Running regression models using STATA
- Reviewing literatures, and editing a research paper

MPH Practicum- GRID (Global Renal Information Database) Project

Oct. 2013- Present

Chronic Kidney Disease outcome research and management in developing countries

Harvard Medical School, Boston, and JHSPH, Baltimore

- Reviewed literatures and guidelines of Chronic Kidney Diseases
- Quantitative data analysis using STATA
- Writing and presenting reports

Graduate Research Assistant

Aug. 2013- Present

Community Based Primary Care Literature Reviewer JHSPH. Baltimore

- Reviewed articles relevant to Community Based Primary Health Care (CBPHC)
- Extracted detailed information and data, and finished the review forms independently

HIV Research Assistant

Centers for Disease Control, Tianiin, China

Nov. 2011- Oct. 2012

- Searched and Reviewed literatures from database
- Extracted, analyzed data from papers

Research Lead

The Influence of Atorvastatin on the Arterial Elasticity of Coronary Heart Disease Patients with or without Diabetes East Hospital of Tongji University, Shanghai May 2011- May 2012

- Designed the study, screened and grouped the patients based on their medical history
- Communicated with physicians and patients to conduct the testing of Brachial-Ankle Pulse Wave Velocity

Xuan Zhang

(baPWV)

• Collected, analyzed the testing data and medical history information

Investigation of Spine Diseases among the University Students

May 2010- May 2011

Tongji University, Shanghai

- Conducted literature review for about 40 papers and summarized the state-of-the-art research progress about spine diseases
- Designed questionnaires, collected and analyzed the data

Volunteer

HIV Consultant online Volunteer

Sept. 2012- Present

Prevention Through Education (NGO), Chicago

- Consultant for people having HIV related issues
- Assisted managers maintaining website
- Coordinated volunteers and customers

Family Medicine Trainee and Volunteer

Annual Shanghai SINO-US Family Medicine Symposium, Shanghai, China

Oct. 2012

- Awarded the Certificate of Standardization of Primary Care and Training
- Volunteered in the symposium and received the scholars in family medicine from worldwide

Internship

Public Health Intern

Centers for Disease Control, Shanghai, China

May 2013- June 2013

- Follow-up, surveillance, data management for non-infectious chronic diseases
- Reviewed literature and extracted information for non-infectious diseases in Baoshan District
- Edited paper of burden of Colorectal Carcinoma
- Learned and applied Statistics software (Excel, Access, SPSS)
- Second Prize of Preventive Medicine paper

Medical Rotation

University of Nebraska Medical Center, Omaha, NE

April 2012- July 2012

• Rotated in diagnostic radiology, neurology and adult cardiology departments

East Hospital of Tongji University, Shanghai, China

Jan. 2012- Jan. 2013

- Clinical rotations as a medical student
- Volunteered to translate medical terminologies for international medical students during rotations

Medical Intern

Heilongjiang Province Hospital, Harbin, China

Sept. 2009- June 2013

- Built portfolios and did data entry of residence' health conditions
- Followed up hypertension patients in Prevention and Healthcare Department
- Diagnosed respiratory system infection, acute abdomen, and other diseases in Internal Emergency Department

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Language Skills: English (Fluent), Mandarin (Native, First Class in Chinese National Test)

Computer Skills: STATA, SPSS, VB, Microsoft Office (Access, Word, Excel), SAS (Expected May, 2014)

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

- Liming Zhu, **Xuan Zhang**, Xin Li. Analysis of Epidemiological Trend for the Colorectal Cancer death and YPLL in Baoshan District of Shanghai. Journal of Environmental & Occupational Medicine, Submitted
- Wang Xu, Cao Sirui, Xuan Zhang, Fang Hongxia, Wang Xiaoqing, Fu Yanyong, Pang Xuewen, Zhan Siyan. A
 Systematic Review about Therapeutic Regimen in Death Rate of TB/HIV Co-infected Patients China Chronic
 Diseases Prevention and Control, Vol 21 (2), April, 2013
- **Xuan Zhang**, Zuanshen Chen, Xinglun Liang. Family Medicine in the UK, USA and Australia and Its Implications for China, *Yiyao Qianyan (Advanced Medicine)*, Vols. 2011, 01(24)
- **Xuan Zhang**. The Influence of Atorvastatin on the Arterial Elasticity of CHD Patients with or without DM, *Overseas English*, ISSN 1009-5039, CN 34-1209/g4, page 285-286, Vols. 17, September, 2012